The terrifying motion picture from the terrifying No. 1 best seller.
Jaws is a horror, thriller, adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg.
When the seaside community of Amity finds itself under attack by a dangerous great white shark, the town's chief of police, a young
marine biologist, and a grizzled shark hunter embark on a desperate quest to kill the beast before it strikes again.
Brody, played by Roy Scheider.
Quint, played by Robert Shaw.
Hooper, played by Richard Dreyfuss.
Ellen Brody, played by Lorraine Gary.
Vaughn, played by Murray Hamilton.
Meadows, played by Carl Gottlieb.
Jaws is a 1975 American  thriller film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Based on the 1974 novel by Peter Benchley, it stars Roy Scheider as police chief Martin Brody, who, with the help of a marine biologist (Richard Dreyfuss) and
a professional shark hunter (Robert Shaw), hunts a man-eating great white shark that attacks beachgoers at a New England summer resort town.
Murray Hamilton plays the town's mayor, and Lorraine Gary portrays Brody's wife.
The screenplay is credited to Benchley, who wrote the first drafts, and actor-writer
Carl Gottlieb, who rewrote the script during principal photography.
Shot mostly on location at Martha's Vineyard in Massachusetts from May to October 1974, Jaws was the first major motion
picture to be shot on the ocean and consequently had a troubled production, going over budget and schedule.
As the art department's mechanical sharks often malfunctioned, Spielberg decided to mostly suggest the shark's presence,
employing an ominous and minimalist theme created by composer John Williams to indicate its impending appearances.
Spielberg and others have compared this suggestive
approach to that of director Alfred Hitchcock.
Universal Pictures released the film to over 450 screens, an exceptionally wide release for a major studio picture at the time,
accompanied by an extensive marketing campaign with heavy emphasis on television spots and tie-in merchandise.
Regarded as a turning point in motion picture history, Jaws was the prototypical
summer blockbuster and won several awards for its music and editing.
It was the highest-grossing film in history until the release of Star Wars two years later; both films were pivotal in establishing the modern Hollywood business model, which pursues
high box-office returns from action and adventure films with simple high-concept premises, released during the summer in thousands of theaters and advertised heavily.
Jaws was followed by three sequels, none of which involved Spielberg
or Benchley, as well as many imitative thrillers.
In 2001, the Library of Congress selected it for preservation
in the United States National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of dying and death, beach,
based on novel or book, bathing, shipwreck.
The tone is dark and intense.